Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Advertising Columnists Articles, 1985-1999
J. Walter Thompson Company. Advertising Columnists Articles 1985-1999
J. Walter Thompson Company.
6 Linear Feet 3600 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Advertising Columnists Articles were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from the Information Center of J. Walter Thompson Company, Chicago Office as a gift in 2000.
Biographical Note
Advertising columnists wrote daily newspaper columns on advertising and closely related subjects.
Collection Overview
Collection of photocopies of thousands of daily columns on advertising and closely related subjects appearing in major newspapers, primarily the Chicago Sun-Times, the Chicago Tribune, and the New York Times. The most frequently represented authors are: George Lazarus ( Tribune, 1985-1999), Nancy Millman ( Sun-Times, until 1992), and Philip H. Dougherty ( NYT, died 1988 September), as well as Randall Rothenberg, Kim Foltz, and Stuart Elliott, who succeeded Dougherty at the Times. Various guest columnists also wrote occasionally for the NYT. For the time period covered, the files appear to contain most or all of the columns that were published in the three papers. The collection also includes several folders of articles and columns from the Wall Street Journal and other business publications, especially concerning management turmoil and succession at J. Walter Thompson Company in 1987. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, and Marketing History.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Lazarus, George
Millman, Nancy
Rothenberg, Randall
Elliott, Stuart
J. Walter Thompson Company
Advertising agencies
Advertising
Journalism
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2001-0123
  - Chicago Sun-Times
    - Nancy Millman, 1985 January-1985 August, 1986 January-1992 May (Box 1)
  - Chicago Tribune
    - George Lazarus, 1985 January-1999 August (Box 1-2)
  - New York Times
    - Philip H. Dougherty, 1986 May-1988 September (Box 2-3)
    - Randall Rothenberg, 1988 October-1990 September (Box 3)
    - Kim Foltz, 1990 October-1991 May (Box 3)
    - Stuart Elliott, 1991 June-1999 August (Box 3-4)
  - Wall Street Journal
    - A variety of columnists including Joann Lipman, 1987 January-December 1987 (Box 4)
      Includes a range of articles addressing upheaval at the J. Walter Thompson Company.
  - Misc. Columns
    - A variety of columnists, 1987 May-1987 June (Box 4)
      Includes various articles addressing the WPP takeover of the J. Walter Thompson Company.